一九六九年三月三日
美國海軍為戰機師成立了一間精英學校
目的是向機師傳授將失傳的空戰技巧
以確保在此畢業的一小部分機師
成為世上最一流的戰機師
他們成功了
現在海軍稱之為戰鬥機武器學校
戰機師則稱之為頂級機師部
壯 志 淩 雲
印度洋  近期
-Morning, Scott  -Morning, Vince
-史葛  早  -溫斯  早
-Morning, Wells  -Morning, sir
-威斯  早  -長官  早
Ghost Rider, this is Strike
騎鬼者  這兒是空襲部
We have unknown aircraft Inbound, Mustang
發現不明戰機  回程的戰機
Your vector, 0-9-0 for bogey
循0-9-0航線飛向敵機
Who's up there?
上面的是誰?
Cougar and Merlin and Maverick and Goose
美洲獅、灰背隼  馬華力和野鵝
Great Maverick and Goose
好極了  是馬華力和野鵝
Talk to me, Goose
野鵝  快回答
Roger, I got him.Contact, 20 left at 30 miles
收到  我發現他了  在左側二十度  三十英里外
Nine hundred knots closure
以九百時速海裡飛近
Cougar, you hear that?
美洲獅  你聽到了嗎?
Roger
收到
-Merlin, you got him?  -Roger, I've got radar contact
-灰背隼  看到他了嗎?  -收到  雷達探測到了
I'll get a visual ID.Cougar, you hook him
我要親眼確定他  美洲獅  你去引他上釣
Roger, and I'll clean him and fry him
收到  我會將他煎皮拆骨
Mustang, Mustang, this is Ghost Rider, 2-0-3,
長官  我是騎鬼者  我們在2-0-3航線
I've got him inbound, bogey heading 2-7-0,
我控制住他了  他以2-7-0航線前進
We're at ten miles, 900 knots closure,
我們相距十英里  以九百海裡的速度靠近
Ghost Rider, take Angels ten left, 3-0
騎鬼者  向左十度  3-0航線
Are we supposed to have visitors today?
我們今天應該有訪客嗎?
Negative, sir
沒有  長官
-Merlin, see if he's a single  -Roger
-灰背隼  看看他是不是一個人  -收到
Goose, you see a trailer?
野鵝  你發現有尾隨的嗎?
Negative, Merlin
沒有  灰背隼
Looks like he's a single
似乎只有他一個
Cougar, I'm gonna go head-to-head with him
美洲獅  我要和他正面交鋒
Take it easy, Maverick I don't like this shit
馬華力  別亂來  我不同意
I'm gonna break high and right,see if he's really alone
我飛高一些  確定是不是只有他一個
We've got 1000 knots closure, Mav
馬華力  我們以一千海裡的速度接近
He's coming right at us
他朝著我們飛過來了
Okay, buddy, what's on your mind?
兄弟  你在想什麼?
Holy shit, there's two of them
天啊  他們有兩個人
MiG-28s No one's been this close before
是米格28  沒人試過這麼近
What the hell are they doing here?What's the position?
他們究竟在做什麼?什麼位置?
Two hundred and fifty miles out, sir
距離二百五十英里
Two hundred and fifty miles? Get them out
二百五十英里  叫他們馬上離開
Cougar, you've got MiG one.I'm going after MiG two
美洲獅  你負責米格戰機一號  我去追米格戰機二號
I lost him in the sun
他在陽光下不見了
Shit What's he doing? You got him, Merlin?
該死  他在做什麼?灰背隼  你發現他了嗎?
He's coming around.He's coming around on our tail
他飛來飛去  他到我們後面了
Goddamn it This bogey's all over me
該死  我被他控制住了
-What's their range now?  -Two hundred miles, sir
-現在他們距離多遠?  -二百英里  長官
If they break 150 miles, launch the Alert Five aircraft
如果小於一百五十英里就出動五號戒備機
Yes, sir
是  長官
Air speed, 300 Go get him, Mav
速度三百  馬華力  消滅他
I'm going for missile lock
我準備進行導彈鎖定
Let's see if we can scare this guy out of here
看看能不能把他嚇走
Come on, lock up, baby.Lock up, baby Lock up
來吧  鎖定他  親愛的  鎖定他
I got him locked Bingo
已經鎖定他了  好極了
We got him, Mav He's bugging out and going home
嚇倒他了  馬華力  他夾著尾巴逃走了
Mustang, this is Maverick MiG two is headed home
長官  我是馬華力  米格戰機二號走了
All right What's their position?
好吧  他們的位置在哪?
A hundred and eighty miles at bearing 0-1-0, sir
距離一百八十英里  航線是0-1-0
Cougar, he's got missile lock on us.Get away from this guy
他的導彈瞄準我們了  快點避開他
What the hell is this shit? He's engaging me
這是怎麼一回事?他追著我
Goddamn it, Mustang.This is Ghost Rider, 1-1-7
該死  長官  這是騎鬼者  航線1-1-7
This bogey's all over me
我被敵機控制住了
He's got missile lock on me Permission to fire?
他用導彈鎖定我了  能允許我開火嗎?
Do not fire until fired upon
未受攻擊前不能開火
Goose, there they are, right below us
野鵝  他們就在我們下面
The MiG's in perfect firing position.He's right on Cougar's tail
米格戰機到最佳的開火位置上了  他在美洲獅後面
No way, Goose.He'd have fired by now
不對  野鵝  他早就應該開火了
He's just trying to piss us off
他只是想激怒我們
Maverick, get down here and get this asshole off me
馬華力  快來幫我脫身
Easy, Cougar
美洲獅  別緊張
Bring it back, hard right Help me engage
帶他回來  協助我進入戰場
I'm on my way
我來了
I can't shoot this son of a bitch
我不能攻擊這個狗娘養的
Let's see if we can have a little fun with him
看看我們能不能跟他玩玩
Is this your idea of fun, Mav?
你說的"玩玩"就是這樣?
Greetings
你好啊
Watch the birdie
看這裡
Jeez, I crack myself up
天啊  笑死我了
This is a great shot, Mav I should be a photographer
這場景太精彩了  我應該當攝影師
Cougar
美洲獅
your tail is clear MiG one's bugged out
你脫身了  米格戰機一號離開了
Cougar, this is Maverick
美洲獅  我是馬華力
We've had enough fun for one day, don't you think?
今天玩得真開心  是嗎?
I'm getting a little low on fuel, so we're heading home
燃料不多了  我們回去吧
We'll see you on deck
在甲板上見
Cougar, we're running low on gas,we gotta get out of here
美洲獅  燃料不多  該走了
Cougar
美洲獅
We're on vapor, Cougar Let's do it
快沒燃料了  美洲獅  快回去
Cougar Come on, Cougar
美洲獅  快啊
Let's take it back to the ship, man, Come on, Cougar,
快飛回艦上  美洲獅  快
Get him on deck as soon as possible.He's gotta be low on fuel
叫他儘快降落  他快沒燃料了
Cougar, we gotta land this thing
美洲獅  我們要降落了
We are way low on gas You understand me?
我們快沒燃料了  你明白嗎?
You all right, man?
你沒事吧?
Maverick, you're at three-quarters of a mile, call the ball,
馬華力  還有四分三英里  降落時作出請示
Roger Maverick has the ball
收到  馬華力請求降落
Cougar, it is time to land, Let's do it,
美洲獅  應該降落了  快點
Goose, Cougar's in trouble
野鵝  美洲獅出事了
Come on, Mav, we're getting low on gas.Let's land this sucker
別亂來  我們快沒燃料了  快點降落
Cougar
美洲獅
Goddamn it, Maverick
該死  馬華力
What are you doing, Mav?we've got no fuel for this
你在做什麼?我們不夠燃料這樣做
We're going after Cougar
我們要去幫美洲獅
You tell him to land that plane That's an order
叫他馬上降落  這是命令
Ghost Rider, you are instructed to land,
騎鬼者  命令你降落
Land immediately,
馬上降落
Any of you boys seen an aircraft carrier around here?
你們看到附近有航空母艦嗎?
Mav, we got a little problem up here.That MiG really screwed him up
我們有點小問題  那架米格戰機嚇壞他了
I don't think he can make it back
他大概無法把戰機開回去
You're okay, Cougar Just stay on my wing,
美洲獅  不要緊  跟著我飛
I'll take you all the way in Just stay with me
我會帶你回去  跟著我
Easy, Cougar Just a walk in the park, buddy
別緊張  好像逛公園一樣
You're a little low.You're a little low, Coug
你飛得低了點  低了一點
Come on, buddy, pull up
夥計  快點拉升
Pull up, Cougar
快點拉升  美洲獅
That's it Almost there
對了  快到了
You're a little below glide path, three-quarters of a mile,
你比跑道低了點  還有四分三英里
Call the ball,
請求降落
Roger, ball,
收到  准許降落
We're too low, Cougar.We're too low, Cougar
美洲獅  我們太低了
Increase power Some more power!
加大動力
Come in
請進
Sir
長官
Cougar, you should be in sickbay.What's on your mind?
美洲獅  你應該在醫護室  你在想什麼?
My wife and kid, sir
我的妻兒
I almost orphaned him today, and I've never even seen him
他今天幾乎變成孤兒  我還沒見過他
I don't know what happened up there, but I was so scared
我不知道發生了什麼事  但是我很害怕
-Come on, we've seen this before  -No, sir
-別這樣  我們以前也見過這種事  -不  長官
I'm holding on too tight
我的壓力太大了
I've lost the edge I'm sorry, sir I'm sorry
我已經受夠了  對不起  長官
Cougar
美洲獅
Thanks, Maverick
謝謝  馬華力
Maverick, Goose, come in here
馬華力、野鵝  進來
-What the hell's going on?  -I don't know
-發生了什麼事?  -我不知道
Shit
該死的
Maverick, you just did an incredibly brave thing
馬華力  你剛才做的事很勇敢
What you should have done was land your plane
可是你應該做的是降落
You don't own that plane, the taxpayers do
戰機是納稅人的  不是你的
Son, your ego is writing checks your body can't cash
你真是狂妄自大
You've been busted.You lost your qualifications as section leader three times
你曾被降職  你三次失去當小組隊長的資格
Put in hack twice by me
我兩次幫你恢復職位
With a history of high-speed passes over five air-control towers
你卻試過高速飛過五個控制塔
and one admiral's daughter
和上將的女兒
Penny Benjamin?
彭妮·本傑明?
-And you, asshole You're lucky to be here  -Thank you, sir
-你這笨蛋能在這兒真是走運  -謝謝
Let's not bullshit, Maverick,your family name ain't the best in the Navy
不說廢話了  馬華力  你的名字不是空軍中最響亮的
You need to be doing it better and cleaner than the other guy.
你應該做得更好
Now, what is it with you?
你究竟在想什麼?
Just wanna serve my country,be the best fighter pilot in Navy, sir
我只想為國效力  當最好的海軍戰機師
Don't screw around with me, Maverick
馬華力  別想騙我了
You're a hell of an instinctive pilot Maybe too good
你全憑直覺駕駛戰機  而且很出色
I'd like to bust your butt, but I can't.I got another problem here
我真想開除你  但是不行  我有了另一個麻煩
I gotta send somebody from this squadron to Miramar
我要從隊中派人去米拉馬
I gotta do something here.I still can't believe it
我要做一些事我難以置信的事
I gotta give you your dream shot.I'm gonna send you up against the best
我要讓你夢想成真  派你去面對一流的海軍
You two characters are going to Top Gun
你們兩個會進頂級機師部
For five weeks,you're gonna fly against the best fighter pilots in the world
你們會和世界上的頂級機師交手五個星期
You were number two, Cougar was number one
你是第二  美洲獅是第一
Cougar lost it, turned in his wings
美洲獅放棄開戰機
You guys are number one
你們就成了第一
But you remember one thing: You screw up just this much,
但記著一件事：你們闖了這麼多禍
you'll be flying a cargo plane full of rubber dog shit out of Hong Kong
遲早會被調去香港運狗屎的
Yes, sir
是  長官
That is all
沒事了
You can tell me about the MiG some other time
改天再向我彙報米格戰機的事
Gentlemen
兩位
-Good luck, gentlemen  -Thank you, sir
-祝你們好運  -謝謝  長官
Thank you
謝謝
美國空軍基地  加州米拉馬
During Korea, the Navy kill ratio was 12-to-1
海軍在韓戰的殺敵比率是十二比一
We shot down 12 of their jets for every one of ours
我們一架戰機就能擊落敵人十二架
During Vietnam, that ratio fell to 3-to-1
到了越戰時比率降至三比一
Our pilots become dependent upon missiles
我們的機師太依賴導彈了
They had lost some of their dogfighting skills
他們失去了一些空戰技巧
Top Gun was created to teach ACM: Air Combat Maneuvering
成立頂級機師部是為了教導你們空戰策略
Dogfighting
也就是空中格鬥
This gives me a hard-on
真令人興奮
By the end of Vietnam, that ratio was back up to 12-to-1
到了越戰末期這一比率回升至十二比一
-Don't tease me  -Blinds, please
-別跟我開玩笑  -請拉開窗簾
I'd like to take this opportunity to introduce you to our commanding officer at Top Gun
我想藉著這次機會介紹指揮官給大家認識
The very first man to win the Top Gun trophy
他是第一位獲得頂級機師獎的人
You will not find a finer fighter pilot anywhere in the world
你不會在其他地方找到比他更優秀的機師了
Commander Mike Metcalf Callsign: Viper
邁克·麥特卡福長官  代號毒蛇
Gentlemen
各位
You are the top one percent of all naval aviators
你們是海軍空戰人員中百裡挑一的
The elite The best of the best
是精英  精英中之精英
We'll make you better
我們會令你們更進一步
You'll fly at least two combat missions a day,
你們每天至少要執行兩項空戰任務
attend classes in between and evaluations of your performance
期間你們要上課聽取對自己表現的評價
On each combat sequence, you're gonna meet a different challenge
你們在每次的空戰任務中都要面對新挑戰
Every encounter is gonna be much more difficult
而每一次都會更加困難
We're gonna teach you to fly the F-14 right to the edge of the envelope,
我們會教你們如何令F14戰機盡展所長
faster than you've ever flown before
你們會比以前飛得更快
and more dangerous
也會更加危險
Now, we don't make policy here, gentlemen
各位  我們不是在這兒制定政策
Elected officials, civilians do that
那是當選的政府官員所做的事
We are the instruments of that policy
我們只是這些政策的工具
And although we're not at war,we must always act as though we are at war
雖然我們不是在打仗  但要時刻保持戰時狀態
What are you doing?
你在做什麼?
-The tip of the spear best be sharp  -I'm just wondering who's the best
-好鋼用在刀刃上  -我只是在想誰是最一流的機師
In case some of you wonder who the best is,
你們可能會想誰是最一流的機師
they're up here on this plaque on the wall
他們的名字就在牆上
The best driver and his RIO from each class has his name on it
最優秀的機師及其通訊員的名字都會記錄在上面
And they have the option to come back here to be Top Gun instructors
他們可以選擇回來當教官
You think your name's gonna be on that plaque?
你認為你的名字會在上面?
Yes, sir
是的  長官
That's pretty arrogant, considering the company you're in
你真是自以為是  周圍有這麼多人
Yes, sir
是的  長官
I like that in a pilot
我喜歡機師自大
Just remember, when it's over out there,we're all on the same team
記著  離開這兒後  我們都是同一隊人
Gentlemen, this school is about combat
各位  這兒是教大家如何戰鬥的
There are no points for second place
當第二名是沒有意義的
Dismissed
解散
Nice going
做得好
The plaque for the alternates is down in the ladies' room
替補的勳章在女洗手間
Oh, Jesus Oh, you kill me You really do
天啊  真是笑死我了
No, no, no There's two O's in "Goose", boys
不...夥計們  "野鵝"可是有兩個O的
This is what I call a target-rich environment
真是一個不愁沒目標的環境
You live your life between your legs, Mav
你在兩條腿之間生活
Goose, even you could get laid in a place like this
野鵝  你也可以來這兒的
I'm telling you, I'd be happy to find a girl who'd talk dirty to me
能找到朝我說髒話的女孩  我就高興了
Mav, you wanted to know who the best is?
馬華力  你想知道誰是一流機師?
That's him Iceman
就是他  冰佬
That's the way he flies, ice-cold, no mistakes
因為他開戰機時十分冷靜  從不犯錯
Just wears you down.You get bored, frustrated,
磨滅你的耐性  令你沮喪
do something stupid, and he's got you
你一犯錯就會被他逮住
Hey, hey, Slider
滑行者  你好
Thought you wanted to be a pilot, man What happened?
我還以為你想做機師呢  發生了什麼事?
Goose, you're such a dickhead.Whose butt did you kiss to get in here?
野鵝  你真是個蠢才  你是靠誰進來的?
Well, the list is long but distinguished
名單很長  不過很有名
Well, so is my johnson
我的詹森也是
So you're flying with Iceman, huh?
你和冰佬一組?
-It's Mr Iceman to you  -Hey, Mother Goose How's it going?
-你應該說冰佬先生  -野鵝媽媽  你好嗎?
Good, Tom This is Pete Mitchell,Tom Kazansky
很好  湯姆  這位是皮特·米切爾  湯姆·卡山斯基
-Congratulations on Top Gun  -Thank you
-恭喜你加入頂級機師部  -謝謝
Sorry to hear about Cougar
美洲獅的事真令人遺憾
He and I were like brothers in flight school
他和我在飛行學校時情同手足
-He was a good man  -Still is a good man
-他以前很棒的  -他現在仍然很棒
Yeah, that's what I meant
我就是這個意思
-Thought so  -Say, you need any help?
-我也是這樣認為的  -需要幫忙嗎?
With what?
幫忙什麼?
You figured it out yet?
你想到了嗎?
What's that?
什麼?
Who's the best pilot
誰是最佳機師
No, I think I can figure that one out on my own
不  我自己會想到的
I heard that about you You like to work alone
聽說你喜歡單獨行事
Mav, you must've soloed under a lucky star, huh?
你一定是在幸運星之下行事
I mean, first the MiG,and then you guys slide into Cougar's spot
我的意思是  先是米格戰機  然後又闖進了美洲獅的戰場
We didn't slide into Cougar's spot.It was ours, okay?
我們不是闖進去  那也是我們的戰場
Some pilots wait their whole career just to see a MiG up close
有些機師到退役時還沒試過近距離接觸米格戰機
Guess you guys are lucky and famous, huh?
你們一定是既幸運又出名了
No, you mean notorious
你想說的是臭名昭著吧
-I'll see you later  -You can count on it
-再見  -一定會的
They were abused children
他們被人寵壞了
-We're gonna have a good time  -Always
-我們會有一段好時光  -總是如此
Okay, I guess it's my turn, isn't it?
這次應該輪到我了吧
All right, the bet is $20
好吧  賭二十元
-Twenty dollars  -Right
-二十元  -對
You have to have carnal knowledge,of a lady this time, on the premises
你得對欲望有所認識才能在此刻勾搭上女人  就這麼說定了
On the premises
說定了
Come on, Mav A bet's a bet
來吧  這只是一場賭博
I don't know, it just--It just doesn't seem fair For you, I mean
我不知道  只是...只是這似乎對你不太公平
But she's lost that loving feeling
但是...她失去了愛的感覺
-She's lost--? No, she hasn't  -Yes, she has
-什麼?不  她還沒失去  -她失去了
-She has not lost that-- -Goose, she's lost it
-她還沒失去...  -野鵝  她失去了
Mav--Come on
馬華力  你少來了
I hate it when she does that Shit
該死  我討厭她這樣
Excuse me, miss
對不起  小姐
Hey, hey, hey.Don't worry, I'll take care of this
別擔心  我會幫你搞定的
You never close your eyes anymore
你不再閉上雙眼
When I kiss your lips
當我親吻你的雙唇
There's no tenderness like before
你的指尖不再溫柔
You're trying hard not to show it
你努力掩飾
Baby
親愛的
But, baby, believe me, I know it
可是  相信我  我知道的
You've lost that loving feeling.That loving feeling
你已經失去了愛的感覺
You've lost that loving feeling
你失去了愛的感覺
Now it's gone, gone, gone
感覺一去不返
Sit down
坐下吧
Thank you
謝謝
Baby, baby, I get down on my knees for you
親愛的  我會為你下跪
I love that song I've never seen that approach
我喜歡這首歌  從沒見過這種搭訕
How long have you two been doing this act?
你們兩個試過多少次?
-Oh, I don't know, since  -Puberty?
-我不知道  從…  -青春期開始?
Right, puberty
對
-I'm Charlotte Blackwood  -I'm Maverick
-我叫夏洛特·布萊克伍德  -我叫馬華力
Maverick? Did your mother not like you or something?
馬華力?你媽媽不喜歡你嗎?
No, it's my callsign
不  這是我的代號
-You're a pilot  -That's right, a naval aviator
-你是戰機師  -是的  我是海軍空戰人員
No, actually, we've only done this twice
其實我們這樣做只試過兩次
Oh, how'd you do?
結果怎樣?
Crashed and burned on the first one It wasn't pretty
第一次是一場大災難  不太好看
-The second?  -I don't know I'll tell you tomorrow
-第二次呢?  -我不知道  明天告訴你
But it's looking good so far
但暫時來看還不錯
Well, Maverick,
馬華力
my friend's just arrived, so it's been great talking to you
我的朋友到了  和你聊得很愉快
-Perry  -Hi
-彼利  -你好
Hi Here you go I'll be with you in just a second, okay?
你來了  我馬上過去
Listen, can I ask you a personal question?
我可以問你一個私人問題嗎?
That depends
那要看你問什麼
Are you a good pilot?
你是個好機師嗎?
I can hold my own
我認為我是
Great
好極了
Then I won't have to worry about you making your living as a singer
我不用擔心你要以唱歌來謀生了
I'm gonna need a beer to put these flames out Yo!
我需要啤酒來滅火
Great, Mav Real slick
好極了  真狡猾
It was a long cruise, was it, sailor?
水手  你出海太久了嗎?
It was too long
太久了
What did you wanna do,just drop right down on the tile and go for it?
你想怎樣  就地進行嗎?
No, I actually had--Had this counter in mind
不  其實我是想在這張桌子上
Great, that would be very, very comfortable Yeah
好極了  一定會很舒服
It could be
可能會
Actually,I came in here to save you from making a big mistake with that older guy
其實我來是希望你不會為那個老鬼做錯誤的決定
Really?So I could go on to a bigger one with a young guy like yourself?
真的?那我就能和你這種年輕人好了?
Maybe No?
可能吧
I've gotta be at work very early in the morning
明天一早我便要工作
Then what are you doing here?
你在這兒做什麼?
Your friend was magnificent
你的朋友真厲害
No
不
Now, you'll also be trained and evaluated by a few civilian specialists
你們也會受到獨立專家的訓練和評估
The civilians are here because they are our very best source of information on enemy aircraft
這兒有非軍事人員是因為他們對敵機很有認識
One of the most qualified is our TAGREP,callsign: Charlie
其中最有資格的就是教官代表  代號狐狸
She has a PhD in astrophysics,
她是天體物理學博士
and she's also a civilian contractor,so you do not salute her
她也是一個非軍事人員  你們不用向她敬禮
But you better listen to her,because the Pentagon listens to her about your proficiency
不過最好聽她的  因為軍方相信她對你們的評估
-It's all yours, Charlie  -Thank you
-交給你了  狐狸  -謝謝
Hello
大家好
We will be dealing with F-5s and A-4s as our MiG simulators
我們會用F5和A4模擬米格戰機
Now, then, as most of you know,
你們大多都應該知道
the F-5 doesn't have the thrust-to-weight ratio the MiG-28 has
F5不具備米格28的推重比
And it doesn't bleed energy below 300 knots, like the MiG-28
更不會像米格28那樣  在低於三百海裡時放出能量
However, the MiG-28 does have a problem with its inverted flight tanks
不過米格28的反向飛行油箱確有問題
It won't do a negative-G pushover
它不擅長做負引力飛行動作
The latest intelligence tells us that the most it will do
最新的情報告訴我們它最多
is one negative--
能夠連續做一個負...
Excuse me, lieutenant
對不起  上尉
Is there something wrong?
有什麼問題嗎?
Yes, ma'am, the data on the MiG is inaccurate
女士  米格戰機的資料不正確
How's that, lieutenant?
哪兒不正確?
-Well, I just happened to see a MiG-28 do-- -We, we
-我看過米格28做..   -是我們
Sorry, Goose
對不起  野鵝
We happened to see a MiG-28 do a four-G negative dive
我們見過米格28連續做四個負引力俯衝
Where did you see this?
你在哪兒見到的?
-That's classified  -It's what?
-這是機密資料  -什麼?
It's classified
是機密資料
I could tell you, but I'd have to kill you
我可以告訴你  但是之後就要殺了你
Lieutenant, I have top-secret clearance
上尉  我有權知道最高機密
The Pentagon sees to it that I know more than you
軍方要我比你知道得更多
Well, ma'am, it doesn't seem so in this case, now, does it?
那麼這次大概不同了
So, lieutenant where exactly were you?
上尉...你當時在哪兒?
-Well, we  -Thank you
-我們...  -謝謝
started up on his 6 when he pulled through the clouds,and then I moved in above him
當他穿越雲層時  我們在他後面  然後我飛到他上面
Well, if you were directly above him, how could you see him?
你在他上面又怎會看到他?
-Because I was inverted  -Bullshit
-因為我倒轉了  -廢話
No, he was, man It was a really great move
不  他真是這樣做的  很精彩呢
He was inverted
他倒轉了
You were in a four-G inverted dive with a MiG-28?
你倒轉著和米格28一起做四個負引力俯衝?
Yes, ma'am
是的
-At what range?  -About two meters
-距離多遠?  -大概兩米吧
It was actually about one and a half, I think
實際上應該是一米半
It was one and a half.I've got a great Polaroid of it
是一米半  我拍下了當時的精彩景象
He's right there It must be one and a half
他沒錯  一定是一米半
-It was a nice picture  -Lieutenant
-是張好照片  -上尉
What were you doing there?
你當時在做什麼?
-Communicating  -Communicating
-溝通  -是溝通
Keeping up foreign relations
保持外交關係
I was You know, giving him the bird
我當時在向他喝倒彩
-You know, the finger  -Yes, I know the finger, Goose
-用手指表示  -我明白  野鵝
I'm sorry, I hate it when it does that I'm sorry
對不起  我討厭它這樣
Excuse me
對不起
So you're the one
原來是你
Yes, ma'am
是的  女士
All right, gentlemen, we have a hop to take
好吧  各位  我們要飛行了
The hard deck on this hop will be 10000 feet.There'll be no engagement below that
這次飛行的強制高度在一萬英尺  無論如何不能低於這個高度
Move it
出發
Lieutenant
上尉
Okay, well, don't be late again.You look great, honey
別再遲到  親愛的
Thanks, dear See you in preflight
謝謝  在預飛區見
Lieutenant,why didn't you tell me that you were the famous MiG insulter?
上尉  你為什麼不告訴我米格戰機是被你羞辱的?
Would it have made any difference?
我說了會有分別嗎?
Not in the ladies' room, no
在女洗手間裡就不會
What would've?
那我們會怎樣呢?
I'm an instructor at this school
我是這兒的教官
I see 20 new hotshots every eight weeks
每八個星期就會見到二十個雄心勃勃的新丁
Now, I'm sure you can figure that out
你一定能想像得到
Look, lieutenant
上尉
I'd just really like to hear about the MiG sometime
我真的很想聽聽米格戰機的事
You've got security clearance.You can read about it
你有權看最高機密  你可以自己看
Maverick
馬華力
I'm curious
我很好奇
Who was covering Cougar while you were showboating with this MiG?
你戲弄米格戰機時  是誰在掩護美洲獅?
Cougar was doing just fine
美洲獅表現很好
Gentlemen, this is your first hop,
各位  這是你們在這的第一次飛行
The jets you are flying against are smaller, faster and more maneuverable,
你們面對的戰機更小、更快  也更容易控制
just like the enemy MiGs,
就像米格戰機一樣
The clock is ticking and as of now,we are keeping score,
計時開始  我們將記錄你們的成績
I lost him, Goose
他不見了  野鵝
Show me what you got, kid
小子  讓我看看你有什麼能耐
-I lost him  -I'm looking, I'm looking
-他不見了  -我在找他了
I got him, I got him.He's on our tail, coming hard
看到了  他在我們後面  沖過來了
I got him I got him Here we go
我看到他了  行動
All right, talk to me, Goose
好吧  野鵝  告訴我現在的情況
He's still back there He's closing in on us.He's closing fast
他仍然在後面  在不斷接近我們  速度很快
You can run, kid, but you can't hide
小子  你可以逃  但是躲不掉
Come on, Jester.Let's see if I can give you a run for your money here
來吧  小丑  看看我能不能逼你使出全力
Watch the mountains
小心撞到山
I still got him He's still back there
他仍然在後面
Come on, Mav Do some of that pilot shit
馬華力  快點想辦法
Yeah, I got him
我看到他了
Come on, bring it right
來吧  快鎖定它
Goose, I've had about enough of this shit
野鵝  我受夠了
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by
我要拉制動器  他就會飛過頭
Okay, you're mine
你們死定了
Jesus Christ
天啊
Let's see what you've got now, Jester
看看你現在的境況  小丑
Okay, Mav, let's turn and burn
讓我們扭轉局勢吧
He's going vertical, so am I
他垂直飛  我也來
We're going ballistic, Mav Go get him
我們好像導彈一樣  咬住他
He's going for the hard deck.Let's get down there first and nail him, Mav
他要飛越強制高度了  快搶先一步  釘住他
No way, Jester, you're mine
想都別想  小丑  你死定了
I got you now
我瞄準你了
Jester's dead
小丑輸了
Get your butts above the hard deck and return to base immediately
馬上拉升  飛離強制高度範圍  回基地
Yes, sir
遵命
Tower, this is Ghost Rider requesting a flyby
控制塔  騎鬼者請求飛越
Negative, Ghost Rider, the pattern is full
騎鬼者  不行  航線繁忙
No No, Mav This is not a good idea
不  馬華力  這不是個好主意
Sorry, Goose, but it's time to buzz the tower
對不起  野鵝  是時候飛過控制塔了
Goddamn son of a bitch
臭小子
Great balls of fire!
真是精彩絕倫
Jester's dead
小丑輸了
-You won? That's bullshit  -Didn't everybody?
-你們贏了?胡說  -不是大家都贏了嗎?
Hell, no, man, we got our butts kicked
贏了才怪  我們都慘敗而回
Thirty seconds We went like this, he went like that
在三十秒內我們往這邊飛  他往那邊飛
I said to Hollywood, "Where'd he go?"Hollywood said, "Where'd who go?"
我問好萊塢他在哪兒  他竟然問我誰在哪兒?
Yeah, and he's laughing at us,right on the radio He's laughing at us
他就在對講機上取笑我們
No, it's me laughing, dickhead
不  笑你們的是我  笨蛋
-We won  -All right
-我們贏了  -好啊
They won too, man
他們也贏了呢
-That's not what I heard  -No, we did, we got Jester
-我沒聽說  -是真的  我們打敗了小丑
No, no Below the hard deck does not count
不  低於強制高度的不算
Hard deck, my ass.We nailed that son of a bitch
強制高度?總之我們打敗了他
-You guys really are cowboys  -What's your problem, Kazansky?
-你們真愛自吹自擂  -卡山斯基  你有什麼問題嗎?
You're everyone's problem
你是大家的問題
That's because every time you go up in the air,you're unsafe
因為有你  每次飛行都不安全
I don't like you because you're dangerous
我不喜歡你  因為你很危險
That's right, Iceman
對  冰佬
I am dangerous
我很危險
Maverick, you and Goose get your butts out of that flight gear
馬華力  你和野鵝馬上脫掉飛行衣
and up to Viper's office now
到毒蛇的辦公室
Remember, boys, no points for second place
記著  當第二名是沒分的
-You're a lot brighter than you look  -You shut up, okay?
-你們要比看起來聰明  -閉嘴
-Don't worry, Goose, don't worry  -Okay, I will
-別在意  野鵝  -好吧
Two of your snot-nosed jockeys did a flyby on my tower at over 400 knots!
這兩個自大狂  以四百多海裡的速度飛過控制塔
I want somebody's butt I want it now I've had it
我要你們馬上找人負責  我受夠了
Goddamn it! That's twice
該死  第二次了
I want some butts!
一定要有人負責
Well, that'll just about cover the flybys
好吧  這也要算在賬上
Follow me
跟我來
Gentlemen You had a hell of a first day
兩位  你們第一天過得真充實
The hard deck for this hop was 10000 feet
這次任務的強制高度是一萬英尺
You knew it, you broke it
你們明知故犯
You followed Commander Heatherly below after he lost sight of you and called no joy
希瑟利軍官看不見你們後  你們跟在他後面低飛
Why?
為什麼?
Sir I had Commander Heatherly in my sights.He saw me move in for the kill
長官  我看到了希瑟利軍官  他看到我飛到能開火的位置
He then proceeded below the hard deck
就飛越過強制高度
We weren't below 10000 for more than a few seconds
我們只有幾秒的時間低於一萬英尺
I had the shot, there was no danger, so I took it
我瞄準了他  見沒有危險就開火
You took it And broke a major rule of engagement
你開了火  同時你破壞了重要守則
Then you broke another one with that circus-stunt flyby
飛越控制塔時又犯了另一條
Lieutenant Mitchell, Top Gun rules of engagement exist
米切爾上尉  守則是為了
for your safety and for that of your team
你和你的隊員的安全而設定的
They are not flexible, nor am I
守則不可以隨時更改的  包括我在內
Either obey them or you're history.Is that clear?
不遵守的話就要被開除  清楚了嗎?
Yes, sir
是  長官
Dismissed
出去
I really enjoyed that, Mav, thanks a lot
我真的很高興  謝謝你
Holy shit
媽的
Maybe I could learn how to be a truck driver
我或者可以學習當貨車司機
Mav, you have the number of that truck-driving school
你有貨車駕駛學校的電話號碼
we saw on TV?Truck Master, I think it is
我們在電視上看到過
I might need that
我可能會需要它
His fitness report says it all.He's a wild card
評估報告顯示他桀驁不馴
Flies by the seat of his pants.Completely unpredictable
他靠直覺開戰機  完全無法預測
-He got you, didn't he?  -Yeah
-他嚇倒你了?  -是的
Maverick I flew with his old man
馬華力  我曾經和他爸爸共事
Tell me one thing.If you had to go into battle, would you want him with you?
告訴我  你想和他一起上戰場嗎?
I don't know
我不知道
I just don't know
我真的不知道
-You still awake?  -Yeah
-還沒睡嗎?  -是的
What's up?
有什麼事嗎?
Can't sleep
睡不著
You know, when I first realized that we were going to Top Gun,
當我知道可以進頂級機師部時
all I could think about was getting that trophy
我只想著拿機師獎
I gotta be straight with you, Mav
我要坦白跟你說
Right now, I just hope we graduate
現在  我只希望我們能畢業
I got a family to think about.I can't afford to blow this
我有家人  我不能浪費這個機會
Yeah, I guess that flyby wasn't such a big hit
其實飛越控制塔不算什麼
Look, man, I know it's tough for you
我知道你很難受
They wouldn't let you in the academy because you're Duke Mitchell's kid
他們因為你是杜克·米切爾的兒子而不讓你進海軍學院
You have to live with that reputation
你要承受這個汙名
But it's like every time we go up there,it's like you're flying against a ghost
我們每次飛行時  你都像是在和鬼魂開戰一樣
It makes me nervous
你令我緊張
You're the only family I've got
我只有你這個親人
I'm not gonna let you down I promise you
我不會令你失望的  我保證
Get out of here
回去吧
A rolling reversal would work well in that situation
在那種情形下反向翻轉會很有效
If I reversed on a hard cross,I could immediately go to guns on them
如果我做十字形翻轉就能馬上開火
Yeah, but at that speed, it's too fast
但在這種速度下  太快了
It's a little bit too aggressive
而且太過急進
Too aggressive
太過急進?
Yeah, I guess when I see something,I go right after it
我覺得應該做的  就會去做
You didn't tell me who you were the other night
那晚  你沒告訴我你是誰
You didn't give me a chance, did you?
你沒有給我機會說
You deserved it
是你的責任
I know But you were tempted to ask me out for dinner
我知道你不過是想要約我吃晚餐
-No  -No?
-不  -不?
No I don't date students
不  我不和學員約會
I can see it's dangerous for you
我看得出這對你很危險
But if the government trusts me, maybe you could
但是如果政府相信我  你也可以
It takes a lot more than just fancy flying
這不只是像花式飛行那麼簡單
今晚五點半共進晚餐
Crash and burn, huh, Mav?
一敗塗地  馬華力?
Slider
滑行者
you stink
你很臭
Let's go
開始
Okay, Ice, hit it
冰佬  快打
That's good Come on
好樣的  繼續
Let's go, now
快  來吧
Come on, Mav, 4-7 Let's get them.Those guys are animals
馬華力  四比七  讓我們宰了他們  他們都是些畜生
Let's go
來吧
Good serve, good serve
好球  好球
That's game
那就對了
Okay Fake block, stay down.We'll just take them
好吧  我們要打敗他們
Come on, where you guys going?You walking away?
來啊  你去那?想跑嗎?
We won, we won
我們贏了  我們贏了
Mav Mav Come on, man.Just one more game That evens it up
馬華力  再打一局  就追成平手了
-Come on, we can take them  -No
-來吧  我們能打敗他們  -不行
-No, we can, we got it  -I got some things I gotta take care of
-來吧  我們能贏他們  -我有事要辦
Take care of? Just one more game
有事?就再打一局而已
-Please? For me?  -I'm sorry
-求你了  就算是為了我  -對不起
You're sorry Come on
你是該內疚  來吧
-Mother Goose, you pussy!  -For me?
-野鵝媽媽  你的小姑娘呢?  -就算是為了我
Damn it
該死
Lieutenant?
上尉
What, no singing?
不唱歌了嗎?
-Look, I'm--I'm-- -No apologies
-我…  -不用道歉
If you don't mind, I'm--I'm gonna just take a quick shower
你不介意的話  我想去洗一個澡  很快
while you're finishing up here
好讓你把這些弄完
Yeah, I do mind I'm hungry
可是我介意  我很餓
And then I thought about it
後來我想
I thought:
我想：
You know, Charlie, he's a smart guy
狐狸  你知道的  他是個聰明人
Why don't you just tell him why you've got him here"
為什麼不乾脆告訴他  請他來的目的?
Well?
是什麼?
It's the MiG
米格戰機
The MiG
是米格戰機
You're the only pilot who's been up against a MiG-28
只有你曾經面對過米格28
I'm trying for this big promotion at work, and if I get it,
我正為升職而努力工作  如果成功的話
I'm not gonna be here much longer
我不會再留在這兒
It seems to me you've got it all figured out
你似乎什麼都想清楚了
Yeah
是
Except you did forget the wine
只是你忘記了酒
Sorry
對不起
You always get what you want?
你常常如願以償?
No, not always Yeah, maybe
不…可能是吧
Then relax about the MiG
那就別在意那架米格戰機
This music
這首歌…
An old friend?
你很熟悉嗎?
My folks loved it
我父母很喜歡這首歌
I haven't heard this in years
我有很多年沒聽過了
My mother used to call down from her room
媽媽以前在她房裡
and have me play this over and over again
總叫我一邊一邊的放它
I got so sick of it
我很厭倦聽這首歌
But not her, she
她卻沒有…
Just sit up there alone, just listening, hours
她會獨坐在一旁  一聽就是幾個小時
Just listening
只是在那聽
She died shortly after him
他死後不久她也死了
What happened to your father?
你爸爸怎樣死的?
I guess I kind of figured, with your security clearance,
你既然有權知道機密資料
you'd know more about him than I do
應該比我知道得更多
Well, I didn't get that far
我還沒知道得那麼深入
Well, it's a big mystery
這是一個謎
He disappeared in an F-4, November 5th, 1965
他在1965年11月5日開著F4失蹤了
The stink of it was, he screwed up
聽說是他犯錯了
No way
但是那不可能
My old man was a great fighter pilot
我爸爸是很優秀的機師
But who the hell knows?It's all classified
但誰知道呢?一切都被列作機密資料
Somebody must know
一定有人知道的
Yeah, somebody knows everything
有人什麼都知道
Is that why you're always second best up there?
所以你總是只能拿到第二名?
You are direct, aren't you?
你真直接
I'm sorry I was late
對不起  我遲到了
I'm sorry for being direct
對不起  我這麼直接
No apologies
不用道歉
This is gonna be complicated
這會變得很複雜
Where are you going?
你去哪兒?
I'm gonna take a shower
我去洗個澡
Thank you I enjoyed being here
謝謝  我在這很愉快
It looks like you need another shower
你似乎需要再洗一個澡
Right
對
I'm gonna be honest with you
我想對你坦白
Your MiG sighting is really important to my work, but
你見過米格戰機  這會對我的工作大有幫助
I don't normally invite students to my house
但我不是常常請學員  到家中作客的
You're
你是…
But please understand, I still have a job to do
希望你明白我有工作在身
-Morning  -Sir
-早上好  -長官
I'm glad we got that straight
我很高興我們這麼坦白
I told her how tough it is here
我告訴她這兒有多辛苦
You know, my ass dragging like an old, tired dog
我累得跟死狗一樣
I told her that you didn't even have a woman here
我告訴她你在這兒連一個女人也沒有
-Oh, really  -You know what she said?
-真的嗎?  -知道她怎樣說嗎?
Said, "Well, he probably doesn't have one, he's got eight"
他可能有八個呢
Daddy
爸爸
So, Maverick,Goose tells me you're in love with one of your instructors
馬華力  野鵝說你和教官墜入愛河了
-Is that right?  -I--I didn't tell her that
-是嗎?  -我沒說過這件事
Yes, you did
你有說過的
-Yes, you did  -I can't believe you said that
-你有說過的  -你竟然說出來
-That was a secret  -No
-那是秘密  -不
The bogey has good position right here.All right, freeze-frame
敵機處在很好的位置  請定格
Moment of choice
是抉擇的時刻了
The F-14 is defensive
F14處於防守態勢
He has a chance to bug out right here
它有機會立即逃離
Better to retire and save your aircraft
最好先撤退以及保證戰機的安全
than push a bad position
這比處於劣勢要好
Charlie, jump in here anytime
狐狸  你可以隨時補充
Now, you stay in that diamond another three seconds,
你在菱形區域內再多呆三秒
the bogey's gonna blow you out of the sky
就會被敵機消滅
You take a hard right, select zone five,
如果你選擇第五區向右突圍
you can extend an escape
就能拖延時間逃走
You made a bad choice
你作了一個很差的決定
Charlie
狐狸
Aircraft one performs a split S?
一號戰機翻了一個S筋斗
That's the last thing you should do.The MiG's right on your tail
這是你最不該做的  米格戰機就在你後面
Freeze there, please
請定格
The MiG has you in his gunsight  What were you thinking at this point?
你在米格戰機的射程範圍  你現在會想什麼?
You don't have time to think up there
你沒時間在空中思考了
If you think, you're dead
一想就死定了
Well, that's a big gamble with a $30 million plane, lieutenant
用價值三千萬元的戰機打賭  賭得可真大呢
Unfortunately, the gamble worked
不幸地  他賭贏了
The MiG never got a clean shot
米格戰機無法開火
Maverick makes an aggressive vertical move here,
馬華力做了一個激進的垂直飛行
comes over the top,and he defeats the bandit with a missile shot
到了頂部  他用導彈打敗了敵機
The encounter was a victory,
這次的交手是一次勝利
but I think that we've shown it as an example of what not to do
不過這是不應該再做的
Next
下一個
Gutsiest move I ever saw, man
從沒見過這麼大膽的舉動
Now, then, this is a perfect example of a textbook maneuver
接著的可以作為教科書的最佳案例
Lieutenant
上尉
Maverick
馬華力
Lieutenant
上尉…
上尉
My review of your flight performance in the TACTS was right on,
我對你的飛行評估
in my professional opinion
是我的專業意見
I can't hear you
我聽不到你說什麼
Jesus Christ! And you think I'm reckless
天啊  你以為我只會魯莽行事
When I fly,I'll have you know that my crew and my plane come first!
我飛行時就會讓你知道  我以我的隊員和戰機為先
Well, I'm going to finish my sentence, lieutenant
上尉  讓我把話說完
My review of your flight performance was right on
我對你的飛行評估是正確的
-Is that right?  -That is right
-是嗎?  -是的
But I held something back
但是我有所保留
I see some real genius in your flying,Maverick, but I can't say that in there
我看得出你有飛行的天賦  但是我不能在那兒說出來
I was afraid that everyone in that TACTS trailer would see right through me
我害怕大家會看穿我
And I just don't want anyone to know that I've fallen for you
我只是不想讓人知道  我愛上你了
-Hey, Maverick  -Yeah
-馬華力  -什麼事?
You hear about Ice?
聽說冰佬的事了嗎?
-What's that?  -He won another one
-什麼事?  -他又贏了
-Really?  -Yeah
-真的?  -是的
I feel the need,
我覺得需要
-the need for speed  -The need for speed
-需要速度  -需要速度
Gentlemen, this is hop 19,
各位  這是第十九次飛行
Multiple aircraft, multiple bogies,
會有更多戰機和敵人
Your training is half over,The competition for the Top Gun trophy remains tight,
訓練已經過了一半  最佳機師獎的爭奪仍然激烈
First place, Iceman,
第一名是冰佬
Second place, Maverick, just two points behind,
第二名是馬華力  只差兩分
There they are
他們來了
Three miles, left, 10 o'clock.I don't think they see us yet
在三英里外  十點鐘方向  大概還沒看見我們
Okay, I see them
好的  我看到他們了
Two A-4s, left 10 o'clock level, continue left turn
左邊有兩架A4  在十點鐘方向  繼續左轉
Good morning, gentlemen.The temperature's 110 degrees
各位早上好  氣溫是110度
Holy shit, it's Viper
天啊  是毒蛇
Viper's up here, great
毒蛇在空中  好極了
Oh, shit
該死
Great He's probably saying,"Holy shit, it's Maverick and Goose"
他可能也在說："該死的  是馬華力和野鵝"
Yeah, I'm sure he's saying that
他一定在這樣說
I've got my eye on the northern bogey
我盯住北面的敵機
Roger I got the southern guy
收到  我盯住南面的
Hollywood, you've got the lead, I'll cover you
好萊塢  你先走  我掩護你
Break now, Jester
小丑  現在分開走
Hollywood, we're losing Viper.Let's just stay on Jester
好萊塢  毒蛇不見了  先對付小丑吧
Roger, I'm on him
收到  我去對付他
Goose, find Viper He's out there somewhere
野鵝  把毒蛇找出來  他一定在附近
Stay with Hollywood, Mav, we're covering his wing
和好萊塢一起  我們要掩護他
Goose, there's Viper 3 o'clock, low
野鵝  是毒蛇  他在三點鐘方向
Stay with Hollywood, Mav We're his cover
和好萊塢一起  我們在掩護他
Don't you leave me, Maverick
馬華力  別離開我
Hollywood, you're looking good
好萊塢  你看起來很好
I'm going after Viper
我去對付毒蛇
Goddamn you, Maverick
馬華力  去你的
Mav, don't leave him
馬華力  別離開他
Goose, Hollywood's okay I want Viper
野鵝  好萊塢沒事的  我想打敗毒蛇
Stand by Viper's coming down
準備  毒蛇過來了
Holy shit, we're head-to-head.I can't believe we're doing this
該死  我們面對面了  我們竟然這樣做
Rocking roll Here's our chance.It's a big one, Goose
搖滾一下吧  機不可失  野鵝
Come on, goddamn it
來吧  該死的
Come on, Mav, keep coming
來啊  馬華力  跟著來啊
Okay Sidewinder missile selected
選定響尾蛇導彈
Come on, baby Come on, baby
來吧  親愛的
Come around, come around.That's it, that's it
回來啊  對了
Jesus, this guy's good
天啊  他真厲害
Goose, where's he going?
野鵝  他要去哪兒?
Come on, come on, come on, keep coming Keep coming
來啊  繼續跟著我啊
Come on, baby
來吧  親愛的
Damn, this kid's good
該死  這小子真厲害
He's too close for missiles,Goose, I'm switching to guns
他太接近  不能用導彈  改為用機槍
Come on, come on, come on
快來啊  來啊
Stick with me, stick with me
堅持住  堅持住
What--? Hold it Goose, check our tail
等一下  野鵝  看看後面
Shit There's Jester
該死  是小丑
Bingo, Maverick's dead.You're out of there, kid
成功了  馬華力輸了  小子  你玩完了
Shit
該死
The Defense Department regrets to inform you
國防部很遺憾要告訴你
that your sons are dead because they were stupid
你的兒子因為太笨而戰死沙場
Great balls of fire
真刺激
Okay, knock it off, gentlemen.Let's go home Viper has the lead
算了吧  大家回去  由毒蛇帶頭
Thirty seconds, Wolfman, and I'm coming in
還有三十秒  人狼  我要進來了
-Shut up!  -God, buttnose
-閉嘴!  -天哪  該死的
That was some of the best flying I've seen yet,
我從沒見過這麼精彩的空戰
right up the part where you got killed
直至你們被打敗為止
You never, never leave your wingman
你永遠不該離開同伴
Maverick
馬華力
it's not your flying, it's your attitude
問題不在你的飛行技術  而是你的態度
The enemy's dangerous,but right now you're worse than the enemy
敵人很危險  但是你比敵人更加危險
You're dangerous and foolish
你既危險又愚蠢
You may not like the guys flying with you,
你未必喜歡你的隊友
they may not like you, but whose side are you on?
他們也未必喜歡你  但是你究竟是哪一方?
Well, at least Viper got Iceman before he got us
起碼毒蛇在打敗我們之前打敗了冰佬
We still got a shot at it
我們仍然有機會得獎
That was stupid I know better than that
那是愚蠢的行為  我是知道的
It'll never happen again
不會再發生這種事了
I know
我知道
我知道的
Maverick, would you go fetch him?Doesn't he ever embarrass you?
馬華力  快去制止他吧  他沒使你難為情嗎?
Goose? Hell, no Well, there was the time
野鵝  當然沒有  不過  有時候…
-Admiral's daughter  -What?!
-上將的女兒  -什麼?
Come on
承認吧
He told me all about the time you went ballistic with Penny Benjamin
他把你飛過彭妮·本傑明的事告訴我了
Did he? Well, that's great
是嗎?好極了
He tells me about all of them, Maverick
他把一切都告訴我了
How my little angel Goose goes home early for church,
我的小天使野鵝早早回家準備去教堂
and you, you always go home with the hot women
你就常常帶火辣辣的女人回家
All right, thank you, Carole
好吧  謝謝你  嘉露
I'm gonna go embarrass myself with Goose for a while
我去和野鵝一起難為情
I would love to be able to warn you off about Maverick,
我想警告你  馬華力很危險
but I just love him to death
可是我很喜歡他
You know, I've known Pete for a lot of years now,
我認識皮特很多年了
and I'm telling you, one thing's for certain
有一件事我可以肯定的告訴你
There are hearts breaking wide open all over the world tonight
今晚世界上會有很多人心碎
-Why?  -Because unless you are a fool,
-為什麼?  -因為…除非你是個笨蛋
that boy is off the market
他已經不再在情場上鬼混了
He is 100 percent, prime-time in love with you
他是百分百、史無前例地愛上了你
Hey, Goose, you big stud!
野鵝  臭男人
That's me, honey
我的確是  親愛的
-Take me to bed or lose me forever  -Show me the way home, honey
-和我上床  否則你會永遠失去我  -告訴我怎樣回家  親愛的
Come on, brother, sing with the family
乖兒子  和大家一起唱
Maverick
馬華力
you big stud, take me to bed or lose me forever
臭男人  和我上床  否則你會永遠失去我
Okay, gentlemen, this is hop 31,Two weeks to graduation,
各位  這是第三十一次飛行  你們還有兩星期就畢業了
Top Gun trophy is still up for grabs,  so every point counts,
最佳機師獎的歸屬仍有懸念  每一分都很重要
Well, it's bottom of the ninth, the score is tied.It's time for the big one
還剩九次飛行了  分數咬得很緊  是時候來一次全勝了
You up for this one, Maverick?
馬華力  你這次能贏嗎?
Just a walk in the park, Kazansky
這跟在公園散步一樣容易
Contact Multiple bogies, 1-6-5
呼叫  有多架敵機  1-6-5航線
Two miles Looks like they're going away from us
距離兩英里  他們似乎想遠離我們
Ho, I see them, tallyho, right 2 o'clock I'm in
不  我看到他們了  在兩點鐘方向  我來了
I'm in
我也加入
That son of a bitch cut me off
這個臭小子截住我了
Come on, come on Jesus Christ.Ice, take the shot
快  天啊  冰佬  快開火
Come on, Ice, get the hell out of there
冰佬  快點讓開
I can't get the angle.I'm too close for missiles
我的角度不好  太近了  不能用導彈
I'm switching to guns
現在改為用機槍
Ice, fire or clear
冰佬  你不開火就走開
Look at this! Jesus Christ,I can take a shot right here!
天啊  我在這兒也能開火
I need another 20 seconds, then I've got it
我只需要多二十秒
I'm moving in I've got the shot
我來了  我已經鎖定了
Come on, Mav, let's get in there!Come on, Mav!
馬華力  我們上  快
Maverick's getting impatient.Come on, take the shot
馬華力不耐煩了  冰佬  快開火
Ten more seconds, then I've got him
再多十秒就行了
Come on, Ice, get the hell out of there!Let's do it, Mav
冰佬  快走開  馬華力  出手吧
Ice, come off high right I'm in
冰佬  從右邊走開  我要上來
-Five more seconds  -Come off high right, Ice I'm in
-再多五秒  -去右邊  冰佬  我來了
I'm off Shit!
我走開  該死
-We're in his jet wash!  -Holy shit!
-我們在噴氣流之中  -該死
This is not good Shit, we got a flameout, Mav
情況不妙  該死  引擎停了  馬華力
Engine one is out
引擎一號停了
Engine two is out!
引擎二號也停了
Goose, I'm losing control I'm losing control
野鵝  我無法控制戰機
I can't control it It won't recover
失去控制了  無法回復正常
Shit
該死
It's coupling up, Mav! We're out of control
禍不單行  我們無法控制戰機
This is not good! This is not good!
情況不妙
Mayday, mayday Mav's in trouble.He's in a flat spin
請求救援  馬華力出事了  機身在不停打轉
He's heading out to sea
快掉進海裡了
Altitude 8000, 7000
高度八千  七千
Six We're at six, Mav
現在只有六千
I'm pinned forward, Goose.I can't reach the ejection handle
我被拋到前面  野鵝  我摸不到跳機杆
Goose, you're gonna have to punch us out
野鵝  你把我們彈出去
I can't reach the ejection handle Eject
我摸不到跳機杆  快點
-I'm trying! I'm trying!  -Eject! Eject!
-我在盡力了  -快
Eject! Watch the canopy!
快  小心機艙蓋
Goose! Goose! Oh, no!
野鵝  不
Oh, God! Oh, God! Oh, God
天啊
Sir, let go of him You gotta let him go, sir
請你放手  你要放開他
How you doing?
你怎樣?
I'm all right
我沒事
Goose is dead
野鵝死了
I know
我知道
You fly jets long enough,something like this happens
開戰機開得久了  總會遇到這種事
He was my RIO, my responsibility
他是我的通訊員  這是我的責任
In my squadron in Vietnam,we lost eight of 18 aircraft Ten men
我在越戰的部隊  十八架戰機有八架墜毀  總共十條人命
First one dies, you die too
第一個人死了  你也會死
But there will be others You can count on it
但還有人活著  你可以指望他們
You gotta let him go
放下吧
I think maybe it was my fault
這可能是我的錯
I don't know what the hell went wrong
我不知道是哪兒出錯
I'd like to help I know it's difficult
我想幫你  我知道你很難接受
God, I want him back
天啊  我希望他能活過來
I'll be here if you need me, okay?
你需要我的話隨時找我
God, he loved flying with you, Maverick
天啊  他很喜歡和你並肩作戰
But he'd have flown anyway without you
就算沒遇上你  他也會當機師
He'd have hated it, but he would've done it
雖然他討厭這種事  但他還是會做
We find that the F-14 flat spin was induced
我們發現這架F14的右側引擎
by the disruption of airflow into the starboard engine
捲進了破壞性的氣流
This disruption stalled the engine,which produced enough yaw rate
這種破壞令引擎停轉  出現過多的偏航率
to induce a spin which was unrecoverable
結果令機身不停打轉  無法修正
There was no way Lieutenant Mitchell could either see
氣流導致引擎停轉
or avoid the jet wash which produced the engine stall
不是米切爾上尉可避免的
Therefore, the board of inquiry finds that Lieutenant Pete Mitchell
所以資詢會認為皮特·米切爾上尉
was not at fault in the accident of 29 July
並沒在7月29日的事故中犯錯
Lieutenant Mitchell's record will be cleared of this incident
這次意外不會記錄在米切爾上尉的檔案中
Lieutenant Mitchell is restored to flight status without further delay
米切爾上尉馬上複職
These proceedings are closed
調查完畢
Get him up flying, soon
儘快讓他恢復飛行
Come on, kid, come on Get in there Engage
小子  快點進入戰場
All right, you got a bogey at 2 o'clock low, Maverick
馬華力  兩點鐘方向有一架敵機
You got the angle Piece of cake, pal
你的位置很好  簡直是輕而易舉
Take the shot, kid Take the shot
快開火  小子
You can engage any time, Maverick
馬華力  你隨時都可以開火
Hey, where the hell are you going?
你要去哪兒?
It's not good It doesn't look good
情況不妙
What do you mean, it doesn't look good?It doesn't get to look any better than that
情況不妙是什麼意思?情況好到不得了
Hey, man, we could've had him.Hey, we could've had him, man!
你本來可以擊中他的  我們可以擊中他的
I will fire when I am goddamn good and ready!
我準備好時自然會開火
You got that?!
你明白了嗎?
He can't get back in the saddle Won't engage
他仍然未恢復過來  他不願戰鬥
It's only been a few days
只過了幾天
You know, he just might not make it back
他可能無法恢復過來了
Keep sending him up
多讓他飛幾次
Mitchell
米切爾
I'm sorry about Goose
野鵝死了我很難過
Everybody liked him
大家都喜歡他
I'm sorry
我很難過
Hi, it's Wolfman
你好  我是人狼
Yeah, Maverick just quit
馬華力剛剛退學了
Excuse me
對不起
May I?
我可以坐下嗎?
Please
隨便
I'll have what he's having
和他要的一樣
Hemlock, is it?
是毒藥吧
Ice water
是冰水
You weren't gonna say goodbye?
你不和我道別嗎?
I heard you got that job in Washington Congratulations
聽說你得到華盛頓的工作了  恭喜
Thanks
謝謝
But I wasn't gonna leave without saying goodbye
但是我不會不辭而別
It's good to see you
看到你真好
Thanks
謝謝
Where you going?
你要去哪兒?
You don't even have a ticket, do you?
你連機票也沒有吧
Listen, I've seen all the evidence,and it's not your responsibility
我看過所有證據  這不是你的責任
It's not your fault You're one of the best pilots in the Navy
不是你的錯  你是海軍裡的精英
What you do up there, it's dangerous
你在高空戰鬥是很危險
But you've got to go on
但是你得繼續下去
You don't understand
你不明白
When I first met you, you were larger than life
我剛認識你時你的生活很充實
Look at you
看看你
You're not gonna be happy unless you're going Mach 2 with your hair on fire,
你不過快節奏生活是不會快樂的
-you know that  -No, it's over
-你知道的  -不  完了
-It's just over  -To be the best of the best
-已經完了  -作為精英中的精英
means you make mistakes and then you go on.It's just like the rest of us
就是要犯錯後仍然繼續努力  這對大家來說都一樣
You don't think I know that?
你以為我不知道嗎?
I'm here to help
我是來幫你的
Look, thank you
謝謝你
But if I wanted help, really,I would have asked for it
我需要別人幫我的話  自然會開口
So I'm too late
原來我來遲了
You've already left
你已經離開了
You didn't learn a damn thing, did you?
你什麼都沒學到
Except to quit
你只學會退縮
You've got that maneuver down real well
你真的很擅長做這種事呢
So long, Pete Mitchell
再見了  皮特·米切爾
Well, hi, Maverick, come on in
你好  馬華力  請進
-How are you doing?  -Good
-你好嗎?  -我很好
-Really? You sure you're feeling okay?  -Oh, I feel great
-真的  你真的沒事?  -我很好
Jamie, come on.Can I get you a drink or anything else like that?
珍美  過來  你要喝點什麼嗎?
-No, thank you  -Okay, well, why don't you just make yourself comfortable
-不必了  謝謝  -那好吧  請隨便坐
Mike will be right down
邁克馬上就下來了
Great, thank you
謝謝
I flew with your old man VF-51, the Oriskany
你爸爸和我在奧利士卡尼號的VF-51小隊並肩作戰
You're a lot like he was
你真的很像他
Only better and worse
或多或少
He was a natural heroic son of a bitch, that one
他是一個天生的英雄主義者
So he did do it right
他真的沒做錯
Yeah, he did it right
是的  他沒做錯
Is that why you fly the way you do?Trying to prove something?
所以你這樣開戰機?你想證明什麼?
Yeah, your old man did it right
你爸爸的確沒做錯
What I'm about to tell you is classified.It could end my career
我要告訴你的事是機密  可能會令我丟掉工作
We were in the worst dogfight I ever dreamed of
我們置身於一場我夢寐以求的戰鬥之中
Bogies like fireflies all over the sky
敵機像螢火蟲般佈滿天空
His F-4 was hit, he was wounded,but he could've made it back
他的F4戰機被擊中  他受了傷  他本來可以回基地
He stayed in it, saved three planes before he bought it
但是他留在戰場  在墜毀之前救了三架戰機
How come I never heard that before?
我怎麼會從沒聽說過?
That's not something the State Department tells dependents
州政府不會告訴家屬
when the battle occurred over the wrong line on some map
因為地圖出錯而發生戰事
-So you were there?  -I was there
-你當時在場?  -是
What's on your mind?
你在想什麼?
My options, sir
我的選擇
Simple
很簡單
First, you've acquired enough points to show up tomorrow
你已經拿到足夠分數
and graduate with your Top Gun class
出席明天的畢業禮
Or you can quit
或者退學
There'd be no disgrace That spin was hell.It would've shook me up
這不是丟臉的事  那樣打轉我也會被嚇倒
So you think I should quit?
你認為我應該退學?
I didn't say that
我沒說過
The simple fact is, you feel responsible for Goose,
你覺得是你害了野鵝  你對自己沒信心
Now, I'm not gonna sit here and blow sunshine up your ass, lieutenant
我不會坐在這兒跟你說好話
A good pilot is compelled to always evaluate what's happened
一個好機師必須評估發生的事
So he can apply what he's learned
這樣才能學以致用
Up there, we gotta push it That's our job
到了高空我們就要全力以赴  這是我們的職責
It's your option, lieutenant, all yours
上尉  這全看你的選擇
Sorry to bother you on a Sunday, sir,but thank you very much for your time
對不起  在周日打擾你謝謝你抽空見我
No problem Good luck
不要緊  祝你好運
房子出租
-Gentlemen  -Where's Maverick?
-各位  -馬華力在哪兒?
I don't know where he is
我不知道他在哪
You know what he's planning to do?
你知道他有什麼打算嗎?
Gotta be hard on the guy, though
他一定很難過
Congratulations
恭喜
Thank you
謝謝
-Congratulations  -Thanks, Mav
-恭喜  -謝謝
Sir
長官
Gentlemen
各位
I hate to break up the party before it really gets out of hand,
我討厭要在派對失去控制前把它結束
but there is work to be done
但是我們有事要做
Some of you have to depart immediately
你們有一些人要馬上離開
We have a crisis situation
我們遇上了危機
-Ice, Slider  -Yo
-冰佬、滑行者  -有
-Hollywood, Wolfman  -Yes, sir
-好萊塢、人狼  -是
-Maverick  -Sir
-馬華力  -長官
Maverick, you'll get your RIO when you get to the ship
馬華力  你到航空母艦就會有通訊員
And if you don't
找不到的話
give me a call I'll fly with you
通知我  我和你一起飛
Sir
是
24小時後  印度洋
Gentlemen, this is bull's-eye
各位  這是舷窗
The communication ship SS Layton has become disabled
通訊船SS賴頓號失去控制
and has wandered into foreign territory
漂進了外國海域
A rescue operation is to begin within the hour
一小時內會開始營救行動
Your mission is to give air support to that rescue
你們的任務就是空中支援營救行動
There are MiGs in the area, and tensions are high
該區有米格戰機  形勢十分緊張
If you witness a hostile act, you will return fire
受到襲擊可以還擊
Those MiGs carry the Exocet anti-ship missile
米格戰機有飛魚反艦導彈
They can fire that missile from 100 miles away
他們可在一百英里以外發射導彈
Gentlemen, this is the real thing.This is what you've been trained for
各位  這是真正的戰鬥  這是你們受訓的目的
You are America's best Make us proud
你們是美國的精英  讓我們感到光榮吧
-Ice  -Yes, sir
-冰佬  -是
-Hollywood  -Yes, sir
-好萊塢  -是
Sector two And Maverick,you back them up with Merlin on Ready Five
第二組  馬華力  你和灰背隼做後援
Yes, sir
是
Rise!
起立
-Excuse me, sir  -Yes
-對不起  長官  -什麼事?
This is not personal, but with regard to Maverick,
我不針對人  但是就馬華力來說
is he the best backup--?
他是最好的後援嗎…
I know what's on your mind,Kazansky, just get on it
我知道你在想什麼  總之你照著辦吧
Mustang, can you give me a mode-four check?
軍官  能替我檢查一下嗎?
Voodoo one, you've got a pair of bogies,12 o'clock, 15 miles
伏都一號  有兩架敵機在十二點鐘方向  距離十五英里
Voodoo one, Voodoo one, 0-9-0,radar contact 15 miles
伏都一號  0-9-0航線  雷達顯示在十五英里
They're doing 500 knots
他們的時速是五百海裡
Roger, that's your bogey
收到  那就是敵機
Got them dead ahead, 15 miles,air speed is 600 knots
他們在正前方十五英里  速度六百海裡
Bogies' air speed, 650, We're a little close together,Let's take a wider split,
敵機速度六百五十海裡  我們靠得太近  離遠點
They're at 15000 feet now,dead ahead, ten miles,
他們在一萬五千英尺高空  正前方十英里
Air speed is still increasing,
正在加速
Eight hundred knots Dead ahead, now, eight miles.Dead ahead, now, eight miles
八百海裡  正前方八英里
-Wood, you got them?  -Not yet, I can't see them
-好萊塢  看到他們了嗎?  -還沒看到
They must be close, I'm getting a hard-on
一定是在接近  我很興奮
Okay, Wood, I'm taking the lead.Let's identify them
好萊塢  我先走一步  確定他們的位置
Roger, Ice, you got the lead.I'm on your left side, a little low
收到  冰佬  你先走  我在你左下方
Maverick's up and ready in Alert Five
馬華力已經準備好出動
Good, good
好極了
Hollywood, my bogey's still locked up,He's drifting to the left,
好萊塢  敵機仍被鎖定  他在你左邊
Still maneuvering course 0-9-0,
仍以0-9-0航線飛行
Okay, Wood, let's bring it to the right,and we'll get a better angle on them,
好萊塢  飛向右邊會有較好的角度
Ice, we got a problem here
冰佬  我們有麻煩
Now I'm breaking out four aircraft on the radar
我在雷達上發現了四架戰機
Not one pair, two pair Repeat, four bogies
不是兩架  是四架敵機
Wood, we've got four bogies
好萊塢  有四架敵機
-Wrong! Make that five!  -There's five, sir
-弄錯了  是五架  -是五架  長官
-That's five?  -Yes, sir
-五架?  -是的  長官
Oh, shit!
該死
He's got a radar lock on us!
他用雷達鎖定了我們
Get out of there, Hollywood!Get out of there, goddamn it!
好萊塢  快離開  快避開  去你的
-Break left!  -I'm hit! I'm hit!
-左轉  -被擊中了
We're coming apart!I can't control it! Hold on!
我們被炸爛了  我無法控制戰機
-We're going down!  -Wood's been hit! Wood's been hit!
-我們在下落  -好萊塢被擊中
Shit! Wood's been hit!
該死  好萊塢被擊中
Voodoo one! Wood's been hit!Wood's been hit!
伏都一號  好萊塢被擊中
We've lost Hollywood!Repeat, we've lost Hollywood!
好萊塢被擊落了
-We've lost our wingman,-Launch Maverick on Alert Five
-我們失去了掩護  -叫馬華力出動
Get a bearing on Hollywood and Wolfman
找出好萊塢和人狼的位置
and launch the rescue helicopter immediately,
出動救援直升機
-Maverick's airborne  -Iceman, what's your position?
-馬華力起飛了  -冰佬  你在哪兒?
0-9-0 at 180 miles
0-9-0航線  180英里以外
We're coming in left!
從左邊來了
Three MiGs, dead ahead,coming down the left side
有三架米格戰機在正前方  從左側向下飛
I'm going after them.I'm bringing it around to the left
我去對付他們  令他們飛到左邊
We got four on our tail!That makes six of them!
我們後面有四架敵機  總共是六架
Who do you think is hooking in the guns range?
你認為誰會在射擊範圍之內?
He's firing! Break right!
他開火了  右轉
Mustang, this is Voodoo one, we are totally defensive
我是伏都一號  我們只能防守
-Launch the alert fighters,  -Where are they?
-快出動戒備戰機  -他們在哪兒?
A hundred and sixty miles and closing in fast, sir
從160英里以外高速飛來
Ready Willard and Simkin off CATs three and four
叫韋勒和森堅準備
Maverick's supersonic I'll be there in 30 seconds
馬華力以超音速趕來  三十秒內趕到
Move your ass! Get up here!I'm engaged with five Repeat, five
快過來  我們面對五架敵機
I'm in deep shit!
我身處險境
What about Willard and Simkin?
韋勒和森堅怎樣了?
Both catapults are broken.We can't launch any aircraft yet, sir
兩部發射器都壞了  不能再發射戰機
-How long?  -It'll take ten minutes
-要多久才能修好  -十分鐘
Bullshit, ten minutes.This thing will be over in two minutes Get on it!
十分鐘?兩分鐘內就玩完了  快想辦法
One MiG, 12 o'clock high!One MiG, 12 o'clock high!
一架米格戰機在十二點鐘方向
Watch your back! Watch your back!
小心後面
Break right!
右轉
Shit, that was close!
該死  就差一點
Maverick, how about some help here?
馬華力  快來幫忙
-Where the hell are you?  -Come on, kid, hang in there
-你在哪?  -小子  快過去
Jesus Christ
天啊
Maverick, how about some help?Engage, goddamn it!
馬華力  快援手  快進入戰場  該死
Maverick, we got a MiG on our tail
馬華力  後面有一架米格戰機
Watch out! Watch out!
小心
Shit, we just flew right through his jet wash
該死  我們剛剛飛過噴氣流
Get control, Mav! Get control!
快點控制機身
Good recovery, Mav Okay, let's get in there
我們修正了  現在進入戰場吧
Come on, we gotta help Ice
我們要幫助冰佬
Come on, let's get back in the game, Maverick!
快點回到戰場  馬華力
-Come on!  -No It's no good
-快去  -我辦不到
-Get in there, Maverick!  -It's no good
-快去  馬華力  -不行
Goddamn it! Maverick's disengaging!
去你的  馬華力竟然退縮
I knew it! Shit!
我早就知道會這樣  該死
Goddamn it, Maverick!
去你的  馬華力
Get in there, Maverick!You can't leave him! Come on! Maverick!
回去  馬華力  你不能離他而去
-What the hell are you doing?  -Talk to me, Goose
-你在做什麼?  -野鵝  和我說說話
Get in there, for chrissake!
快回去  為了上帝
-Ice is in trouble!  -Talk to me, Goose
-冰佬有麻煩  -野鵝  和我說說話
Get in there, Maverick!He won't last down there alone!
快回去  馬華力  不能把他一個人留下
Get in the fight, for chrissakes!
回去戰鬥  為了上帝
Maverick! Maverick!
馬華力
Maverick's reengaging, sir
馬華力重返戰場了
I can't get him off my tail!
我無法擺脫他
Ice, I've got your MiG dead ahead.I've got him dead ahead
冰佬  跟著你的米格戰機在我正前方
Good tone I've got good tone
位置不錯  鎖定了
I've got tone! I've got tone! Firing!
鎖定了  發射
-Where? Where are they?  -A hundred and fifty-five miles
-他們在哪兒?  -155英里外
Two MiGs, dead ahead.Closing at 800 miles an hour
兩架米格戰機在正前方以時速八百英里接近
I see them I see them.I'm gonna take them down the left side
我看到了  我要引一架去左邊
Oh, my God
天啊
Ice is right below us.He's got a MiG on his tail
冰佬在我們下面  他後面有一架米格戰機
He's firing! Break left! Break left!
他開火了  左轉
He overshot! He overshot!
射過頭了
Coming in, Ice I'm coming in
冰佬  我來了
I got two MiGs dead ahead
前面有兩架米格戰機
I got him, Mav One MiG passing between us
我看到了  一架從我們倆中間飛過
You got a MiG on your left.On your left! 3 o'clock!
有一架米格戰機在你左邊  在三點鐘方向
He's gonna fire, he's gonna fire!
他要開火了
Maverick, check the guys to the north!Check the guys to the north!
馬華力  小心北面的米格戰機
Banking left Banking left
左轉
There he is Get him, Ice Get him!
他在那兒  冰佬  消滅他
Okay, you guys, I'm coming in!
好  我來了
Maverick, we got a MiG coming around on our tail!
馬華力  有一架米格戰機正飛向我們後面
-We gotta get out of here!  -I can't leave Ice
-我們要離開這  -我不能離冰佬而去
He's still coming around!He's gonna get behind us!
他仍然在轉向  他要到我們後面了
I'm not leaving my wingman
我不會離同伴而去
I'm on his tail I'm on his tail.I'm going for it
我在他後面  我來對付他
I'm going for it.I'm going for the shot right now
我來對付他  我要向他開火
Roger Engaged
收到  準備
I've got radar lock
雷達已經鎖定了
Good tone I'm taking a shot
位置不錯  我要開火了
Fire!
發射
-Bingo!  -Wash that sucker, yeah!
-好棒!  -消滅那個笨蛋了
Ice, watch out  There's a MiG to your right He's firing!
冰佬  小心  你右邊有一架米格戰機  他開火了
I'm hit! I'm hit!
我被擊中了
We're hit in the right engine!
我們的右引擎被擊中
I'm shutting it down
我正在把它關掉
Coming in, Ice Coming in
冰佬  快逃
Ice, that bogey's still behind you.I'm maneuvering for a shot
冰佬  敵機仍然在你後面  我準備開火
Stay with him, Mav, stay with him!
別放過他  馬華力
-Take the shot! Nail him! Nail him!  -Shit Ice, I can't get a tone
-快開火  擊落他  -冰佬  我無法鎖定目標
Shoot, Maverick! I can't get him off my tail!
快開火  馬華力  我無法擺脫他
-Maverick, we're hit! We're hit again!  -It's okay
-馬華力  我們又被擊中了  -不要緊
Both engines are functioning We're okay
引擎仍然能運作  我們沒事
Ice, on the count of three,break hard right!
冰佬  我數三聲後向右突圍
Three, two, one Break right!
三、二、一  向右突圍
Firing!
開火
Damn it, I missed!
該死  打不中
Don't let him go.Keep on him, Mav Keep on him
別放過他  繼續攻擊他
I got him I got him
我看到他了
Here comes a shot
再來一記
Scratch three!
全取三分!
Maverick, move! There's a MiG on your tail!There's a MiG on your tail!
馬華力  快避開  後面有米格戰機
We've got a problem here.We've only got one missile left
我們有麻煩了  只剩下一顆導彈
-Approaching 110 miles, sir  -Goddamn it
-以時速110英里接近  長官  -該死的
I got him! I got him! He's right on us!He's between our tails!
我看到他了  他就在我們後面
Shit
該死
You haven't lost him He's still with us!
還沒甩掉他  他仍然跟著我們
What are you doing?You're slowing down! You're slowing down!
你在做什麼?你竟然減速?
-I'm bringing him in closer, Merlin  -You're gonna do what?
-我要引他飛近一點  -什麼?
This is it, Maverick!
馬華力  是時候了
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by
我要拉制動器  讓他飛過頭
Shit! He's gonna get a lock on us!
該死  他會鎖定我們的
Now!
就是現在
I got a good lock Firing
鎖定了  發射
Scratch four!
全取四分!
Mustang, this is Voodoo three.Remaining MiGs are bugging out
長官  我是伏都三號  剩下的米格戰機都撤離了
Mustang, this is Maverick requesting flyby
長官  我是馬華力  請求飛越
Negative, Ghost Rider The pattern is full
不批准  騎鬼者  航線繁忙
Excuse me Something I should know about?
對不起  有什麼事該讓我知道嗎?
Thank you
謝謝
Goddamn that guy
臭小子
皮特·米切爾－馬華力
You!
你
You are still dangerous
你仍然很危險
You can be my wingman anytime
不過你隨時可以做我的戰友
Bullshit You can be mine
廢話  你也可以做我的戰友
-Maverick  -Sir
-馬華力  -長官
How does it feel to be on the front page of every newspaper
成為所有英文報紙的頭條
in the English-speaking world?
有什麼感覺?
Even though the other side denies the incident,
雖然另一方否認這件事
-congratulations  -Thank you, sir
-恭喜你  -謝謝
They gave you your choice of duty, son
他們讓你選擇你的職位
Anything, anywhere Do you believe that shit?
任何職位  任何地方  你能相信嗎?
Where do you think you wanna go?
你想去哪兒?
I thought of being an instructor, sir
我想當教官
-Top Gun?  -Yes, sir
-到頂級機師部?  -是  長官
God help us
願主保佑我們
Hello, Pete Mitchell
皮特·米切爾  你好
I heard the best of the best were gonna be back here,so
聽說精英中的精英回來了  所以…
This could be complicated
這會變得很複雜
You know, on the first one,I crashed and burned
第一次是一次大災難
And the second?
第二次呢?
I don't know, but
我不知道  不過…
it's looking good so far
暫時看來還不錯